<module>
	<rawname>frogman</rawname>
	<name>Frogman</name>
	<version>1.4.1</version>
	<publisher>Frogman Project</publisher>
	<license>AGPLv3</license>
	<licenselink>https://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl-3.0.txt</licenselink>
	<category>Admin</category>
	<description>Complete PBX control through natural language from a web console, chat platforms, MCP, or any API client. 223 tools built entirely on FreePBX's native interfaces (BMO, GraphQL, AMI, fwconsole).</description>
	<changelog><![CDATA[
		*1.4.1* (223 tools). Fixed: fm_module_install now auto-downloads from the configured repos when a module isn't yet locally available (previously errored out asking the user to run `fwconsole ma download` first), and no longer falsely reports success when `fwconsole ma install` exits 0 on "Cannot find module" — failures are now detected from output text too. fm_show_context ("show asterisk context <name>") was returning "Command 'dialplan show 'name'' failed" because escapeshellarg wrapped the name in single quotes that Asterisk CLI rejects, and its fwconsole context fallback wasn't a real command — rewritten to AMI-only (within the FreePBX walls) with a clean error if AMI is down. UX: fm_list_trunks output gained inline Enable/Disable action chips per trunk based on current state, and bare "enable trunk" / "disable trunk" (no ID) now routes to the trunk list so users can pick the target without having to first remember the ID. Typeahead now also harvests every chat command exposed via the sidebar (data-cmd / data-paste in views/main.php), so adding or removing a sidebar button updates the suggestion list automatically. Help text and sidebar paste templates converted to bracket-placeholder syntax across the board (e.g. "forward [ext] to [number]" instead of "forward 1001 to 5551234567"); chat input now auto-selects the first placeholder after a typeahead pick or sidebar paste so the user can immediately type to replace it; sendMessage guards against unfilled placeholders before they hit the parser. Internal: every fwconsole invocation across 14 tools now routes through a single AbstractTool::runFwconsole() wrapper so a future FreePBX-side change to the binary path or argv shape is patched in one place rather than 16. fm_get_sip_settings stopped reading /etc/asterisk/rtp_additional.conf directly and stopped SELECTing kvstore_Sipsettings — both go through Sipsettings::getConfig() now so storage moves cleanly across FreePBX updates; same tool also strips the leftover "Privilege: Command" header AMI prefixes Command responses with. Typeahead coverage pass: filled gaps for Sangoma Connect (sc status, sangoma connect status), MCP/Connect setup, KB search, DID map, allow/unallow, peak hours, busiest extensions, search/find, export, when-someone-calls wizard, sys info, reset password, revoke token, and need/check reload. Suggestion count grew 164 → 215. New fm_lint_typeahead dev tool walks every parser anchor and reports any whose keyword group has no backtick phrase in helpText, so future commands can't silently slip out of the typeahead. fm_add_ringgroup now normalizes member input across any separator (commas, spaces, mixed, newlines) before joining with the canonical dash so the FreePBX GUI editor stacks extensions one-per-line; previously space-separated input ("create ringgroup 700 with 101 102 103") landed in storage with literal spaces and the GUI rendered them on one line.
		*1.4.0* (223 tools). New: fm_did_destination_map ("did map" / "inbound map" / "where do my dids go") — Mermaid horizontal flowchart of every inbound DID and its first-hop destination, deduped so multiple DIDs into the same RG share one node. Typeahead command suggestions in the chat input — type 2+ chars to see matching commands, ↑↓ to pick, Tab/Enter to fill (164 phrases auto-extracted from help text). UX: rich "show extension" detail with live registration cross-reference, recording mode chips, NAT/codec triple, and quick-action chips at the bottom; "list all dids" now resolves dialplan strings to friendly labels ("ivr-8,s,1" → "IVR: Main-Menu"); Sangoma tools all bulleted-block formatters with phone emoji; trimmed sidebar Commands section from 75 buttons to 10 curated templates (typeahead handles the long tail); cache-busted asset URLs for chat.js/css. Fixed: fm_originate_call ("call X to Y") was double-broken — wrong param names AND wrong arity to astman->Originate; show extension N hit the substring/search pattern before the digit-only get pattern (so "show extension 100" returned 100 + 1100); fm_list_active_calls / fm_whos_on_the_phone / dashboard active-call count all now filter Asterisk internal Message/AsyncGoto worker channels; fm_list_contacts handled User Manager group schema (uid not id, numbers pre-populated) and falls back through fname+lname → displayname → core users.name → "Ext NNNN" instead of rendering empty bold; fm_create_admin Userman + addAMPUser arity for FreePBX 17. Refactor: AbstractTool gained describeDestination and isAsteriskInternalChannel helpers, used by 5 tools — same regex/SQL was previously inlined.
		*1.3.1* (222 tools). Fixed: fm_sip_trace was capturing 0 data on calls placed during the window (grep ran once on the existing log instead of tail-following new lines, plus output-buffering meant short traces never flushed); SaveQuery and DeleteSavedQuery now require confirm:true (audit pass surfaced two write tools missing the dry-run gate). New: guided wizard for "add inbound route" with smart destination shorthand (1001 → from-did-direct,1001,1; vm 1001, rg 600, ivr 1, tc 1) and skippable description prompt; macro wizard infrastructure that chains multiple tools with optional yes/no gates and a single end-of-flow confirmation; first macro "onboard new employee" handles extension + Follow Me + ring group + DID + outbound CID + reload in one flow, surfacing the auto-generated UCP password in a Credentials footer. UI: new Wizards sidebar section in the chat console.
		*1.3.0* Bug-fix and UX release (222 tools). Fixed: ring-timer now actually applies to live calls; outbound caller ID now actually applies; new extensions can now log in to UCP (auto-wired into default groups + extension assignment, auto-generated UCP password surfaced with reset hint); Set Follow Me works from chat as a guided wizard ("set follow me" or "set follow me 1001"); Module install/uninstall/enable/disable/upgrade now route correctly from chat (rebrand straggler); Module upgrade now distinguishes "already up-to-date" from real upgrades and from errors. New: fm_repair_userman_links to backfill UCP wiring on existing User Manager users ("repair userman" / "fix ucp logins"); fm_check_upgrades for an online repo check ("check for upgrades"); list-modules summary view with clickable license-bucket filters; multi-step wizard infrastructure in ChatParser. Auth: API token's level column is now the source of truth for token-authenticated calls (was being silently ignored); localhost-trust resolves to admin.
		*1.2.1* Sangoma Connect status + email-onboarding chain (220 tools): fm_sc_status (SC preflight diagnostic — license, domain, cert, seats, next-step hint with clickable purchase/cert links), fm_set_extension_email (dual-layer email update — userman + voicemail-to-email via Voicemail::updateMailbox), fm_add_extension now always creates a linked User Manager user, fm_update_activation rewritten to use the deployment-ID-based fwconsole activate command (full GUI-equivalent handshake, backgrounded for chat compat — fixes stale-license-cache bug). New ChatParser pending_input mechanism for free-text follow-ups: voicemail-enable → "Add email?" → input prompt with clickable Skip → reload chain. Chat: "sc status", "sangoma connect status", "set email 1099 a@b.com", "add ext 1100 name Foo email a@b.com".
		*1.2.0* Tier 1 Sangoma/DPMA tools (218 tools): fm_diagnose_sangoma_phone (composite — EPM mapping, license, registration, DPMA state, firmware audit, alerts), fm_list_sangoma_phones, fm_get_sangoma_phone, fm_dpma_alerts, fm_dpma_license_status, fm_reboot_sangoma_phone. Chat: "diagnose sangoma 1005", "list sangoma phones", "sangoma phone 1005", "dpma alerts", "dpma license", "reboot sangoma 1005". All BMO-first, AMI for runtime state, no shell-outs.
		*1.1.1* Cap chat/MCP entry points at 256MB so a runaway tool/parser bug fails in ~1s instead of stalling Apache workers
		*1.1.0* Add fm_whos_on_the_phone (212 tools); fix ChatParser OOM from recursive synonym expansion on "create inbound route"; route questions ending with "?" to KB search; security: shell injection fix in FwconsoleCmd, AMI allowlist, input sanitization; tool prefix oc_ → fm_
		*1.0.0* Initial release: 211 tools, MCP server, web console, CLI chat, knowledge base RAG, call flow visualizer, API token auth
	]]></changelog>	<depends>
		<version>17.0.1</version>
		<module>api ge 17.0.1</module>
	</depends>
	<database>
		<table name="oc_audit_log">
			<field name="id" type="integer" unsigned="true" primarykey="true" autoincrement="true"/>
			<field name="tool" type="string" length="100" default=""/>
			<field name="params" type="text" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="user_id" type="integer" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="session_id" type="string" length="64" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="intent" type="text" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="status" type="string" length="20" default="pending"/>
			<field name="detail" type="text" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="created_at" type="integer" unsigned="true" default="0"/>
			<field name="completed_at" type="integer" unsigned="true" notnull="false"/>
			<key name="idx_oc_audit_tool" type="index">
				<column name="tool"/>
			</key>
			<key name="idx_oc_audit_user" type="index">
				<column name="user_id"/>
			</key>
			<key name="idx_oc_audit_session" type="index">
				<column name="session_id"/>
			</key>
			<key name="idx_oc_audit_created" type="index">
				<column name="created_at"/>
			</key>
		</table>
		<table name="oc_sessions">
			<field name="id" type="string" length="64" primarykey="true"/>
			<field name="user_id" type="integer" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="started_at" type="integer" unsigned="true" default="0"/>
			<field name="last_activity" type="integer" unsigned="true" default="0"/>
			<field name="context" type="text" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="status" type="string" length="20" default="active"/>
		</table>
		<table name="oc_saved_queries">
			<field name="id" type="integer" unsigned="true" primarykey="true" autoincrement="true"/>
			<field name="name" type="string" length="100" default=""/>
			<field name="query" type="text" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="param_spec" type="text" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="created_by" type="integer" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="created_at" type="integer" unsigned="true" default="0"/>
			<key name="idx_oc_sq_name" type="unique">
				<column name="name"/>
			</key>
		</table>
		<table name="oc_jobs">
			<field name="id" type="integer" unsigned="true" primarykey="true" autoincrement="true"/>
			<field name="tool" type="string" length="100" default=""/>
			<field name="params" type="text" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="user_id" type="integer" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="status" type="string" length="20" default="queued"/>
			<field name="result" type="text" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="created_at" type="integer" unsigned="true" default="0"/>
			<field name="started_at" type="integer" unsigned="true" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="completed_at" type="integer" unsigned="true" notnull="false"/>
			<key name="idx_oc_jobs_status" type="index">
				<column name="status"/>
			</key>
		</table>
		<table name="oc_aliases">
			<field name="id" type="integer" unsigned="true" primarykey="true" autoincrement="true"/>
			<field name="alias" type="string" length="100" default=""/>
			<field name="tool" type="string" length="100" default=""/>
			<field name="default_params" type="text" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="created_by" type="integer" notnull="false"/>
			<key name="idx_oc_alias_name" type="unique">
				<column name="alias"/>
			</key>
		</table>
		<table name="oc_api_tokens">
			<field name="id" type="integer" unsigned="true" primarykey="true" autoincrement="true"/>
			<field name="username" type="string" length="100" default=""/>
			<field name="token" type="string" length="64" default=""/>
			<field name="description" type="string" length="255" notnull="false"/>
			<field name="level" type="string" length="20" default="read"/>
			<field name="active" type="integer" unsigned="true" default="1"/>
			<field name="created_at" type="integer" unsigned="true" default="0"/>
			<key name="idx_oc_token" type="unique">
				<column name="token"/>
			</key>
		</table>
	</database>
	<menuitems>
		<frogman category="Admin">Frogman</frogman>
	</menuitems>
	<console>
		<command>
			<name>frogman:tool</name>
			<class>Tool</class>
		</command>
		<command>
			<name>frogman:chat</name>
			<class>Chat</class>
		</command>
	</console>
	<supported>
		<version>17.0</version>
	</supported>
</module>
